Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/xeniawong (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Branding & Identity Information Design Graphic Design

Languages

Mandarin Cantonese English

Certifications

Learning to Set Display Type

Honors-Awards

AIGA Blue Ridge Flux 2018 Design Competition

Xenia W.

Visual Designer (Contract) at Meta San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Xenia is an SF-based multidisciplinary graphic designer from Hong Kong with both digital and print design backgrounds.

With about 5 years of experience, she creates brand & identity, information & icon, presentation, social media marketing, motion graphics, print & digital solutions for startups, design studios, brand consultancy, printing & publishing company, and large international companies.

With a high dedication to detail, she is passionate about translating ideas into minimal, systematic, and thoughtful designs.

Experience

Meta

Visual Designer (Contract)
March 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)
Menlo Park, California, United States

Visual Designer in the VS Iconography Team at Meta, employed by TEKsystems.

Self Employed
Graphic Designer
June 2018 - Present (4 years 11 months)

As a multidisciplinary graphic designer, I design various forms of storytelling, visual identities, brand systems, color guidelines, iconography, print collateral, presentation, corporate reports, social media marketing, email campaign, motion graphics and etc.

Clients Include Ureeka, Fremont Bank, Hero Collective, Uber, Facebook, Hint Water, Streamlinevents, Centric Brands, Quartet Health, Ruder Finn, Kitchen NY Brand Studio, KCSA Strategic Communications, Environmental Defense Fund, and The Ford Foundation.

Eargo

11 months

Senior Graphic Designer
June 2021 - December 2021 (7 months)

San Jose, California, United States

Working closely with the marketing and email design teams, I concept and design multimedia projects for external and internal purposes, including marketing campaigns, social media marketing, email, A/B test direct mail, brand book, motion graphics for how-to videos, etc.

Senior Graphic Designer February 2021 - May 2021 (4 months)

Creative Huddle
Brand Design Lead
September 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 4 months)
Remote

Uber

Presentation Designer November 2019 - November 2019 (1 month) San Francisco Bay Area

- 1) Process and format data of global employee handbook for 24 languages
- 2) Design the Annex book aligning with the handbook design style

Facebook

Communication Designer
August 2019 - September 2019 (2 months)
Menlo Park, California

Designer @Creative Services for the Oculus Connect 6 Conference 2019, Contracted by Creative Circle.

Hint Inc.

Graphic Designer
July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)
San Francisco, California, United States

- 1) Create an email design style guide with the understanding of the existing brand guidelines
- 2) Design infographics for the new side brand hint Green
- 3) Design email campaigns and promotional assets

streamlinevents, inc.
Graphic Designer
April 2019 - July 2019 (4 months)
Emeryville, California, United States

- 1) Design materials and create prototypes for event design, e.g. signage, menu, brochure, etc.
- 2) Manage and categorize photo for file organization

Vaudeville Ventures
Design Intern
August 2017 - April 2018 (9 months)
Greater New York City Area

Vaudeville Ventures is a brand strategy consultancy that provides creative solutions from brand strategies to product designs for clients.

I created visual designs for large and small companies. I designed online promotional materials, brand guidelines and landing page designs for Comcast LIFT Labs and marketing and brand materials for MGM Stargate.

Besides creating graphic materials, I also established projects from ideation to implementation. Highlights are icon designs for Adverator.com and a lookbook design for an upcoming movie Swan Song directed by Todd Stephens.

Hung Hing Off-Set Printing Co., Ltd.
Junior Designer
January 2016 - February 2017 (1 year 2 months)
Hung Hing Printing Centre

Hung Hing Offset Printing Co Ltd is one of the largest printers in Asia with its headquarter and design team in Hong Kong, manufactories in China and sales departments around the world.

I developed projects from bouncing out ideas, data analysis, sketching, prototypes, materials selections to final outcomes. My works included print, digital, interactivity, animation, sales promotion and marketing.

I also conducted meetings with clients and worked closely with factory workers and purchasing colleagues to achieve projects deadline and output quality.

Hong Kong Arts Festival Society Ltd Design Intern May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months)

Page 3 of 5

Hong Kong

Hong Kong Arts Festival is a non-profit organization, is a major international arts festival presenting leading local and international artists in performing arts in February and March each year.

I developed marketing and promotion materials, included corporate presentations, proposals and videos for the internal meetings. Besides, I designed print advertisements and developed the corporate visual identity to enhance brand adherence, awareness and art investment fund.

Young Online Association Thangka Painter June 2015 - July 2015 (2 months) Shangrila

That was a one-month study trip during Summer 2015. I stayed in a local studio located in a remote and secluded area in Shangrila, Yunnan for a month. I explored the authentic Tibetan Buddhist art "Thangka painting" which used mineral pigments as coloring.

Though the experimental presentation inspired me a lot, its cultural connotation impressed me the most. While I was learning and practicing their way of painting, I felt their passion and spirit that made me calm.

Design Creation Innovation Limited Junior Designer July 2014 - February 2015 (8 months) Hong Kong

Design Creation Innovation Limited is a start-up design agency offering a range of design and digital marketing services for clients mainly in Hong Kong and China.

With the supervision of my creative director, I was an one-man crew designer responsible to help clients translate marketing objectives into creative solutions, e.g. designed branding and motion graphics for AXA Insurance, created identity design and web designs for a local E-commerce store, produced product photography and made social media plans and managements.

Education

Maryland Institute College of Art

Bachelor of Fine Arts - BFA, Graphic Design · (2018 - 2018)

The Hong Kong Polytechnic University
Higher Diploma, Multimedia Design and Technology (specialize in Visual Communication) · (2012 - 2014)